German Parlatto

Front-End Software Engineer

+7 years of experience with JavaScript. As a creative and innovative thinker, I bring a unique perspective to every project I work on. With a passion for problem-solving, I am constantly exploring new and unconventional solutions to complex challenges.

germanparlatto@gmail.com



31124940

Copenhagen, Denmark



germanparlatto.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Engineer

AutoRemind S/A 🗷

11/2021 - Present

Copenhagen, Denmark

Is a health care industry, patient communication environment

- I improve the delivery process of new features successfully by implementing feature flag concept on front end. Reducing feature delivery time in production
- I've built a rich text editor from scratch with success.Improving the user experience and reducing the time of template emails creation. What attracted new customers.
- I was in charge of the research and development for a cross-platform app similar to WhatsApp with success. It's was built in Tauri, a cross framework and React with Next.js as web framework, that engage the communication flow between doctor and patients. What attracted new customers.
- I led the decision making process regarding tech stack to migrate an Angular app to React using Next. is as framework whit success.

Front-End Engineer

Cerved Group s.p.a 🗹

05/2020 - 10/2021

Turin, Italy

A Italian fin-tech, provides customers with services, advice and digital platforms to manage risks and sustain data-driven growth

- Optimisation of client-facing assets, while considering user experience with a solid Design System.
- Building new features for the product call CreditBoard with ReactJS.
- Code review and testing within the team.
- Using TypeScript as language to write Reacts components.

Full-Stack Developer

HERMES REPLY @

10/2019 - 04/2020 Turin, Italy

A Italian company specialised in Application Maintenance services for Automotive & Manufacturing industry and Management Consulting services.

- Design and implementation of custom web components and user interfaces built with Angular 9, Angular Material UI component library.
- Building applications for the automotive industry using ReactJS and Redux. Testing these components with Jest.
- Integrating third-party libraries and widgets into the Angular application.
- Working in the automotive business model as production quality workflow and reporting graphics to analyse the performance.

Front-End Engineer

Fujitsu 🗷

01/2018 - 05/2019

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- A Japanese multinational information technology equipment and services company
- Implementation of features and user interface for the main platform (built with Angular 4 frontend and Java REST backend).
- Integration with own and 3rd party cloud applications through APIs.

User requirement specification for Toyota Argentina.

Design and implementation of workflows using the RunMyProcess platform.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer

ITsynch 🗷

06/2016 - 01/2018 Argentina

A company that provides integration with ERP, custom software development and consultancy mainly to large cruise industriy companies.

- Implementation of features and user interface (built with a C# WebApi backend, and an AngularJS frontend).
- Collaboration in the design and UX for new applications.
- Deployment of applications on remote servers.
- Version control and work management carried out using TFS(Team Foundation Server).

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems Engineering (Computer Engineering)

National Technological University - UTN 🗷

02/2010 - 12/2018

LANGUAGES

English Italian Spanish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End JavaScript, Typescript, ReactJS, Redux, **Back End** NodeJS, C#, .NET Framework, API REST, GraphQL, Microservices Architecture, T-

SQL, mongoDB

NextJS, GastbyJS Angular, Webpack, HTML5, CSS3, Jest, cross-platform, Micro-

frontends

Agile, SOLID, OOP, Progressive Web Apps, **Principles &** Methodologies

Web Apps, Responsive Design, TDD,

Design System